star

You may hear that     you must 'step on every square' on this level - not so. At A thru G
    are eight symbols - CRYSTAL, DRAGON, TEMPLE, SERPENT, SPHYNX, STAR,
    CRYPT and BOAT. You MUST step on each of these.

    At I find a button to open a secret door. Step into J and the grate
    will open. Remember? 'You are the Key'. Stop at J, not only to rest 
    fully and set up your best defenses but to do a permanent save. I'll 
    tell you now, there are four (five if you count a duplicate pair) 
    endings to this game. The first dividing point comes at the end of 
    this automated episode, so if you want to check out all the options 
    (and save them for the probable sequel) you need to be able to 
    re-start at this point. And depending on the roll of the random dice, 
    the upcoming battle may be impossible. You need to be able to restart 
    here for that reason, too.

    When you're ready, go to the center of the chamber at K. Search to 
    find a crack in the floor. Use Vitalia's Device to call her. Reply
    'YES' to the questions she asks - "Do you have the keys? - Have you
    tried them? - Shall I try? After all the action is over, Vi will ask
    "Did you find a space ship? (Actually, kind of a dumb question, since
    that's where you got the ring she used to release the GLOBE. Well,
    maybe she doesn't know that.) For now, please answer truthfully - YES.
    (I'll tell you later what happens with a 'NO' answer, and you can
    decide if you want to play out the other endings.) She will tell you
    to go to the spaceship and call her when you're there.

    Find your way back to the entrance and go up the stairs to 63. The 
    quickest way out that I know of is this. Take 43 to level 5, 25 to
    level 4, 50 to level 3, 30 to level 4 and 9 to level 1 and there
    around the corner is the exit to the Chamber of Gorrors. 

    Next stop - SKY CITY. Find your way back to the boat, retrace your 
    way to and through the Dragon Cave and through Sky City to the 
    space ship for the

GRAND FINALE.
    When you get to the space ship you will use Vitalia's Device once
    more to call her. But who shows up but the resurrected Dark Savant
    along with a badly beaten-on Vi Domina. No battle this time, But 
    you have a choice - keep the GLOBE and Vi dies, or give up the globe 
    to the Dark Savant and save the GIRL. If you did a save you can see 
    both endings. The text strongly suggests that you be a hero and save
    the girl. You will have an opportunity to do a special end-game save
    for use in the sequel.
    
    (If you do the unheroic thing and keep the globe, letting Vi die, 
    you will 'float endlessly in space'.)

    Alternate Endings - If you restore from just before getting the Globe,
    and lie - telling Vi you did NOT find a space ship, she will tell
    you to 'meet again where first we met' - The Forbidden Zone in
    New City. This is why you still have the Control Card which is 
    necessary for entry. Again, there are two 'good' endings here, so
    set up a save before entering. After calling Vi, you will go through 
    the same routine as at Sky City, except there will then be a great 
    final battle between the UMPANI and the T'RANG. You must choose 
    between aiding one side of the other. Either way, the side you support 
    will win, and they will give you and Vi a ride to the sequel in their
    ship.